# ALI **TAHIR**

114 Park Lane UB4 8AF · 07475924326 alitahir\_@outlook.com http://alitahir.co.uk

A third-year Computer Science undergraduate at University of Surrey with experience as a Computer Science Lab helper and significant customer service experience. Currently, finished my placement year working as a IT Support Engineer at FootfallCam.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **JULY 2019 - PRESENT**

#### PASSENGER SERVICE AGENT, WILSON JAMES

Ensure a smooth, seamless passenger journey through the airport by assisting, welcoming and engaging with them to deliver legendary service.

#### **JULY 2021 - MARCH 2022**

#### IT SUPPORT ENGINEER, FOOTFALLCAM

Delivered people counting solutions to clients. Helped troubleshoot and diagnose issues clients faced with software.

#### **NOVEMBER 2020 – JANUARY 2022**

# PEER ASSISTED LEARNING SUPPORT, UNIVERSITY OF SURREY

Help students complete lab tasks by answering queries they have. Helped Year-One students undertaking the Web & Database Systems module in Semester One. Currently, helping Year-One students undertaking the Operating Systems module in Semester Two.

# OCTOBER 2020 – MARCH 2021 TUTOR, HESTON LEARNING CENTRE

Tutor students of all ages (KS1 to A-Level) in Mathematics and Physics

# **EDUCATION**

# **OCTOBER 2019 – JUNE 2023**

#### **BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE**, UNIVERSITY OF SURREY

Currently finished my third year, averaged a first-class grade throughout the first two years, on course to achieving a first-class degree.

Relevant modules include Computer Logic, Foundations of Computing I & II, Programming Fundamentals, Web & Database Systems, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Data Structure and Algorithms, Further Programming Paradigms, Information Retrieval, Advanced Algorithms, Web Applications Development, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Networking, Parallel Computing.

The course combines practical projects and theoretical study, developing technical and transferable skills in:

- Web Development Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, XML, jQuery and Ruby
- Programming Languages: Assembly Language, C, C++, Haskell, Python and Java

• Numerical computing Environments: MATLAB, R and SageMath

#### **JUNE 2019**

# A LEVELS, ROSEDALE COLLEGE

- Mathematics A
- Physics A
- ICT B

#### **JUNE 2016**

# **GCSE**, ROSEDALE COLLEGE

- Mathematics A\*
- English Literature A
- Additional Science A
- R.E − A
- Citizenship A
- Statistics A

- French B
- English Language B
- Core Science B
- ICT B
- History B

# **SKILLS**

- SQL
- Java
- Web Design
- Mathematics
- Problem Solving

- Bilingual (English and Urdu)
- Customer Service
- Teaching
- Team Worker
- Communication

# **ACTIVITIES / HOBBIES**

I have gained voluntary work experience at my local bakery, where I developed and deployed an electronic ordering system.

I regularly participate in mathematic challenges and have also taken part in the National Citizen Service. For hobbies, I play club cricket as well as friendlies regularly in the summer season.

# REFERENCES

Available upon request